Christopher Brenton

brentoncchris@gmail.com • (989) 513-3911 • Hazel Park, MI • ccbrenton.github.io

SUMMARY

Multi-disciplinary and solution-driven engineer with 5+ years of experience leading innovation and leveraging data to solve complex problems. Seeking to apply analytical skillset expertise and experience generating value for stakeholders in a transition to data analytics.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Autoliv, Auburn Hills, MI Various Engineering Roles and Promotions

May 2017 - Present

Development Engineer

March 2021 - Present

- Established and maintained a Power BI dashboard and data gateway for all North American engineering director level management streamlining project status insights and necessary corrective actions
- Initiated a time reduction opportunity by creating a data analysis application in Python that reduced the timing for automated test data cleaning and final report generation from a few hours to less than 4 seconds
- Presided as the global leader of illuminated emblems by supporting successful product development, defining internal standards, and managing a team to increase expertise globally
- Championed innovation projects for airbag illuminated emblems as the lead engineer by directing crossfunctional teams, coordinating with suppliers, and managing timing within a budget
- Built an automated engineering data checklist using Excel and VBA, conditional formatting, and data validation to streamline part flagging and reduce user input errors

Development Engineer / Application Engineer

June 2018 - March 2021

- Managed product development for successful launches of the MY19 Lincoln Aviator, MY20 Lincoln Corsair, and the first ever Rivian R1T/R1S steering wheel programs
- Executed product validation testing, conducted analysis on the resulting data, generated final reports based on collected findings, and communicated results to internal and external stakeholders
- Identified trends in the comparison between actual results and predicted results for an armature bending model leading to the implementation of tuning parameters on the model for better future correlation
- Constructed a specialized calculator for all engineering teams based on the Steinhart-Hart equation for converting resistance to temperature using Excel and VBA to correct improper lab calculations

Development Engineer Intern

May 2017 – August 2017

- Designed an innovative method for prototyping parts utilizing 3D printing that resulted in \$60,000 in savings
- Directed a root causing effort to solve a complex plastic deformation issue by utilizing problem solving analysis tools and collaborating with a diverse team of engineers

EDUCATION

Michigan State University, East Lansing, MI B.S. in Mechanical Engineering, Minor in Computer Science May 2018

CERTIFICATIONS, SKILLS & INTERESTS

Certifications: Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate

Hard Skills: Python, VBA, PostgreSQL, Power BI, Microsoft Office, Google Suite, and Windows/Linux/MacOS Proficiency; Tableau, BigQuery, R, MATLAB, C, C++, and Statistics Experience; Machine Learning Familiarity **Soft Skills:** Problem-Solving, Risk Management, Public Speaking, Communication, Collaboration, Solution-Driven, Detail-Orientated, Adaptability, Organization, Self-Motivated, Abstract Thinking, Enthusiasm, Integrity **Interests:** Building Computers, Fantasy Football, Camping, Board Games, Taco Tuesdays